Guide to the Bacon Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence to Reverend Leonard Bacon and family members, 1841-1939; Accession 1996-M-121
  - Phelps, William Walter, 1874 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Porter, Noah, 1850 March 12, 1871 August 15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Silliman, Benjamin, 1841 January 23, 1845 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Silliman, Benjamin, Jr., 1878 August 30-September 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Thompson, Launt, 1874 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Upsala [Archbishop of] [to B. W. Bacon; grandson of Leonard Bacon], 1923 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Walker, James, 1860 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Western Reserve University [President of] [to L. W. Bacon; son of Leonard Bacon], 1895 July 19 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - White, A. D., 1871 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Woolsey, T. D., 1871 August 10, 1891 February 11 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Additional material, 1900-1920; Accession 2017-M-044; .75; (2 boxes)
  This addition to the Bacon Family Papers consists primarily of photographs of a trip to Palestine and Europe taken by Benjamin Wisner Bacon, lectures on religion, and administrative documents regarding the Yale University Divinity School. The bulk of the photographs are of landscapes and ruins; a few photographs include unidentified individuals, as well as some photographs of his children, Dorothy Buckingham Bacon and Benjamin Selden Bacon. This material spans from 1900-1920.
  Separated Materials
  These materials contained silver nitrate negatives of all the photographs that, due to Manuscripts and Archives policy, have been removed from the collection. These negatives contained similar images that are represented in the addition.
  - Entretiens d'ete de l'Abbaye de Pontigry pamphlet, 1910 September (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Europe photographs
    - Coast of Greece, Cape Malea, North of Cape Malea, circa 1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Dorothy Bacon, Rome, other unidentified individuals, 1905 January-August (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Gibraltar and Azores, 1905 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Greece, circa 1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Naples, Greece, scenery and buildings, Circa 1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified women feeding the birds in plazas, possibly Greece?, Circa 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Greece: Corfu photographs, Circa 1910 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Historical Geography of the Holy Land travel journal, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jew and Greek in the Holy Land, 1910 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters from A.C. Williams to Benjamin Bacon, 1910 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Herbert Brown to Benjamin Bacon, 1910 October 22 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Medieval ruins of Kasarich drawing, circa 1910 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Outline of the proposition of the faculty of the Yale Divinity School, circa 1910 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Palestine photographs
    - Aphka - Valley of Nahr Ebrahim from west of Aphka, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Artifact, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Ayassoluk (Selcuk, Turkey), 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Banias trip number 1, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Banias trip number 3, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Banias trip number 5, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Banias trip number 6, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Banias trip number 7, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Beisan, Jezreel, Mount Gilboa, Sea of Galilee, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Beitin from east, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bethlehem area, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bethlehem from Mount Takoa, west Chariton from "Cave of Adullam", 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Boat run - Chanush, Cauldron with Greek inscription, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Boundary stone at Chamish (Charush?) Gorge, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Carmel - rock cuttings with Nahreka in background, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Cave of Samson, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Dorothy Bacon, Tom and baby in Ramallah, Kerak (Jordan), Arnon (Wadi Mujib), 1905–1906 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - East Jordan number 1, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - East Jordan number 2, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - East Jordan number 4, Salim, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Expedition to Ain Karim and Bittir, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Gerash, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Gezer and Artuf trip, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Group at Chanush, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Inscriptions from Haman Museum of SPC Beirut, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Jebeel - Castle from southwest Gebail, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Jebeel - Sarcophagus in tomb, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Jebeel, Maronite chapel at B'lat statue built into the wall, Latin inscription, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Kal'at Niha, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Lifta from Jaffa Road (southwest) Kubeibeh Emmans, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Macceboth near Tomb of Judges, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Mar Saba, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Megiddo, Great Trench, W. Trench, Rock Altar, Maccibah, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Michmash, Wadi Suweinit, Geba, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Nahr Ibrahim + Aphka, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Nazareth, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Rock cut Roman Road and Chanush, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Samos, Burj Far'a, 1900–1920 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Sarcophagus at Sidon (Lebanon), 1900–1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Spring near Acra, ladder of Tyre, 1900–1920 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Tabor from El Fuleh, Nazareth from El Fuleh, 1900–1920 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - West Suweinit + Bozez, Anata, Jordan and Dead Sea, 1900–1920 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Paul des Jardins correspondence, circa 1910 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of unidentified locations
    - Door, 1900–1920 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified men near ruins, 1900–1920 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Probably Europe: house photograph, 1900–1920 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Proposed establishment at Yale of a University School of Religion and Christian Service, 1913 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Reconstruction in the Divinity School lecture, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Reorganization of the Yale Divinity School memoranda, 1910 May 21 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Revue moderniste internationale ire annee n. 9, 1910 September (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Weltkongress fur Freies Christentum und Religiosen Fortschritt pamphlet, 1910 August 10 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Yale School of Religion school information and map of New Haven, 1910 February (Box 2, Folder 14)